(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
目指せよ快眠
Aim for a good night's sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win a peaceful sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
To the world of dreams we go
理想の眠りを求めて
In search of the ideal slumber
さあ　始めよう
Come, let's begin
おやすみ
Good night
ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠...
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep...
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess
魔王の城の中で
Inside the Demon King's castle
独り閉じ込められては
Being locked up all alone,
毎日ひたすらに眠ってます
I spend every single day just sleeping
今宵も布団に入り
Into the futon again tonight,
スヤスヤリスト生活
A peaceful-sleepy-list life
枕も寝室も
Both the pillow and the bedroom
硬くて眠れない
Are too hard for me to sleep
（君も寝具にしてやろうか）
(Shall I turn you into bedding too?)
目指せよ快眠
Aim for a good night's sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win a peaceful sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
To the world of dreams we go
フカフカの枕手に入れて
Get hold of a soft, fluffy pillow
この疲れ癒したい
And heal this exhaustion
恐れず前進　ほぐせよ全身
Move forward without fear, relax your whole body
まぶたを閉じたなら
Once you close your eyelids,
スベスベのシーツの上で
On top of smooth sheets,
さあ　始めよう
Come, let's begin
おやすみ
Good night
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess
悲鳴が響く夜に
In the night where screams echo,
独りで檻を抜け出し
I slip out of my cage alone,
今日もお散歩へと行ってきます
And head out for a walk again today
幾多の試練も越えて
Overcoming many trials,
新たな寝具の前で
In front of new bedding
もっと マグマで
With more magma,
猛毒で
With deadly poison,
死んでも眠りたい
I want to sleep even if I die
寝心地最高にしてやろうか！
I'll make it the best sleep ever!
掴めよ快眠 疲れて安眠
Seize that pleasant sleep, sleep soundly when tired
いざ夢の向こうへ
Now, to the other side of dreams
ハイテク目覚まし 手に入れて
Get a high-tech alarm clock
気持ちよく目覚めたい
And wake up feeling good
まだまだ前進 華麗に変身
Still moving forward, splendidly transforming
ごはんを食べたなら
Once you've eaten your meal
魔法のベッドにダイブして
Dive into the magical bed
さあ 始めよう おやすみ
Now, let's begin. Good night
明日はもっと 今日よりずっと
Tomorrow will be even better than today,
いい夢見れるかな
I wonder if I'll have better dreams
フワフワの羽に包まれて
Wrapped in fluffy feathers
ココロゆくまで眠りたい
I want to sleep to my heart's content
目指せよ快眠 勝ち取れ安眠
Aim for that pleasant sleep, win that sound sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams
理想の眠りを求めて
In search of the ideal sleep
さあ 始めよう おやすみ
Now, let's begin. Good night
もうあと5分 おやすみ
Just 5 more minutes. Good night
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
スヤァ
Syaa
うわぁ〜
Uwaaa~
はい、こんまっする！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルで〜す！
Yes, Kon-muscle! I'm Hololive 3rd Gen's Shirogane Noel!
本日はライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to the live today!
そしてハッシュタグはこちら！
And here is the hashtag!
#白銀ノエル生誕祭2025、たくさんスクショしてSNSに投稿してください！
#ShiroganeNoelBirthday2025, please take lots of screenshots and post them on social media!
今日のライブのテーマなんですが、見ての通りね、睡眠・安眠・癒やしライブとなっております。
As for today's live theme, as you can see, it's a "Sleep, Sound Sleep, and Healing Live."
ライブ後半にかけて盛り上がっていくので、ぜひ皆様も盛り上がってください！
It's going to get more exciting toward the second half, so please join in the excitement!
てな感じで、1曲目は「快眠！安眠！スヤリスト生活」を歌わせていただきました。
And with that, for the first song, I performed "Kaimin! Anmin! Syuallist Seikatsu."
あの曲中のね、団長踊りながら、まあ変身したシーンがありましたけど
During that song, there was a scene where I transformed while dancing,
わかった？わかったっていうか、みんな気づいてる？っていうか、おメイクがちょっと変わりました〜！
Did you catch it? Or rather, did everyone notice? My makeup has changed a bit!
お気づきでしょうか？
Did you notice?
まあ具体的にね、どういうところが変わったかと言いますと
To be specific about what exactly has changed,
あの、髪の毛がですね、あのサラサラに、よりなりました。
my hair has become, well, even silkier.
ええ、サラサラになって、特に後ろとかね、わかるかな？ほら、サラサラ。
Yes, it's so silky. Can you tell from the back? Look, silky smooth.
もう本当に、いつでもあのシャンプーのCM待ってます、てな感じでサラサラになったのと
Honestly, I'm ready for a shampoo commercial offer anytime. Besides being silky,
あとおメイクもね、ちょっと変わっております。
my makeup has also changed a bit.
まあいろんなね、表情ができるようになったんですけど
Well, I can make various expressions now.
えっと、なんか第3ノイちゃんが怒るようなこと言ってみて。お、おん。え、なに？
Um, try saying something that would make "Noi-chan No. 3" angry. Uh-huh. Eh, what?
「おい、ちょっと太った？」
"Hey, did you gain a little weight?"
ん〜！なに！太ってないよ！最近ダイエット頑張ってるもん！
Hmph! What! I didn't gain weight! I've been working hard on my diet lately!
てな感じで、前はちょっと結構ガチ怒りって感じだったんですけど、マイルド怒りになりました。
Like that. Before, it was more like "serious anger," but now it's "mild anger."
はい。っていう感じで、あの、ちょっとね、いろんな表情ができるようになったんで、それも踏まえてライブ見てくれると嬉しいです。
Yes. So, I can make various expressions now, and I'd be happy if you keep that in mind while watching the live.
そして、ま、ノイちゃんも変わったんですけど、この変わったね、お姿でさらに
And while I've changed, in this new form,
本日のステージはこちらです！え〜すごいね、全景、わあ！
here is today's stage! Wow, it's amazing. Look at the whole view!
なんか本当に癒やして感じだよね、もう本当に綺麗に。
It really feels healing, doesn't it? It's so beautifully made.
はい、作っていただきました。ま、このね、周り。
Yes, they made it for me. And look around here.
そう周りにこれ雲。雲の海みたいな感じで、プカプカってなっています。
Yeah, these are clouds around us. It's like a sea of clouds, just floating there.
ええ。そしてね、こうやって雲の海から、上もね、すごい！
Yes. And from this sea of clouds, look up there too! It's amazing!
きれい！なんか飾りがグルグルグルっと回っておりますので
So beautiful! Those decorations are spinning around and around.
やらなんかね、あのこれ、これからちょっとゲストパートとかもあるんですけど
So, well, there's going to be a guest part coming up soon.
なんかそれに合わせて色々と変わってくるみたいなので、ぜひ楽しみにしてみてください。
It seems things will change along with that, so please look forward to it.
それでは次の曲、レッツゴー！
And now, for the next song... Let's go!
僕は今 夢旅の中
I am now in the midst of a dream journey
あの星の島までも
Even to that star island
飛んでゆける
I can fly
手のり歌歌う
Singing a palm-sized song
僕のユメクイ
my Dream-eater
君のそばにも
To your side too
たどり着ける
I can reach
ユメクイ
Yumekui
作詞・作曲: 愛
Lyrics and Composition: Ai
最初に描いた
The dream I first envisioned
夢を思い出せなくなって
I can no longer remember
あとは大人になったから？
Is it because I've become an adult?
えん
*sob*
右か左かで
Whether to go right or left
いつまでも迷って
I'm lost forever
太陽が反転するまで
Until the sun turns around
喋り込んだ
we talked and talked
一つだけポケットに入れてきたもの
The one thing I brought in my pocket
大きなこの愛を持って
carrying this great love
僕は今夢旅の中
I am now in the middle of a dream journey
あの星の島までも
Even to that star island
飛んでゆける
I can fly
手のり歌歌う
Singing a palm-sized song
僕のユメクイ
my Dream-eater
君のそばにも
To your side too
たどり着ける
I can reach
カラフルなモヤに
By a colorful haze
心を奪われ
my heart was stolen
ちょっとしたことに
Over a small thing
躓いた
I stumbled
すり剥いたとこに
On the place I scraped
君がくれたのは
what you gave me was
恥ずかしいくらいの
almost embarrassingly
かわいらしい絆創膏
a cute bandage
叶えるたびに
Every time I make a dream come true
食いつくすユメクイ
the Dream-eater devours it
叶えるたびに また夢を見る
Every time it's fulfilled, I dream again
いくつになっても
no matter how old I get
僕は今夢旅の中
I am now in the middle of a dream journey
寄り道して
Taking a detour
プレゼントを見つける
to find a present
手のり歌歌う
Singing a palm-sized song
僕のユメクイ
my Dream-eater
描いた未来に
In the future I envisioned
君がいつもいる
you are always there
僕は今夢旅の中
I am now in the middle of a dream journey
あの星の島までも
Even to that star island
飛んでゆける
I can fly
手のり歌歌う
Singing a palm-sized song
僕のユメクイ
my Dream-eater
君のそばにも
To your side too
たどり着ける
I can reach
君のそばで
By your side
ずっと夢を見る
I'll dream forever
ユメクイ　ユメクイ
Dream Eater, Dream Eater
バイバイ　バイバイ
Bye-bye, bye-bye
ハンパないっ ぱらっ ぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっ
It's unreal, pa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra
Hey 限界 突破らっ ぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっ
Hey, break through the limit, pa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra
Hey 毎日 ハンパないっ ぱらっ ぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっ
Hey, every day is unreal, pa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra
Hey 限界 突破らっ ぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっ
Hey, break through the limit, pa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra
Hey
最適温度　ふさぎ切るコスト
Optimal temperature, costs that block everything out
八百万の　嫌な外的要素
Countless unpleasant external factors
なんの気ないと　超あっけらかんと
So nonchalantly, so indifferently
悪気もなく　お邪魔するとか　誰かさんにバイバイ
Intruding without any malice, say goodbye to someone
自分時間　だらくタイム確保　5時9時を死守しますと
Secure my personal lazy time, I'll defend my 5-to-9
さらに愛や　恋や　甘いもん忘れずに　とどのつまり
Don't forget love, romance, and sweets, in short
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよ　手注意喚起もしてますよ
Overwork is strictly prohibited, I'm issuing a warning
ねえ楽して　上手くして　生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living life easily and doing it well is hard
だって安手　裏技　一夜漬け　甘い水には罠がある
Cheap tricks, shortcuts, cramming, sweet water has traps
Yeah!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleep when I'm sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Wake up past noon
遊びたきゃ遊ぶ
Play if I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eat when I'm hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laugh when I'm happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
If I'm sad, it's okay to cry, isn't it?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For tomorrow's me, I'll manage to do my best today
明日も頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
Working hard so I won't have to tomorrow
総体じゃないや　これ多分そうだ　なんやでやることやってます
It's not everything, but maybe this is it, somehow I'm getting things done
What? & If?
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
I don't care if no one knows
私には私のマイルール　明日楽するためにはハイチーズ
I have my own rules, say 'cheese' to make tomorrow easier
意外とこんな感じで　ラブアンドピースのある毎日を生きたいのです
I want to live every day like this, with love and peace
Don't be shy　ドキドキしたい
Don't be shy, I want to feel my heart pound
Let me shine　明日天気になれ
Let me shine, let the weather be good tomorrow
To be excite　心もっと踊りたい
To be excited, I want my heart to dance more
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday
辛くなったら歌う
Sing when it's hard
むかついたら愚痴る
Complain when I'm annoyed
やりたいようにやる
Do it the way I want to
それができたら苦労しないわ
If I could do that, I wouldn't be struggling
常に一喜一憂　してりゃ何あろうと思ったんかな
Always swinging between joy and sorrow, I wonder what I thought would happen
適当にセーブ　ディスクは返し　でも頑張るのさ
Save appropriately, return the disk, but still do my best
適当にまでとは言わないが　まぁ頑張るのさ
I won't say I'll be half-hearted, but well, I'll do my best
夢の中では　ずっとぐーたらしてやるんだ
In my dreams, I'm going to be lazy all the time
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく　明日の私のために　Fight
Not for someone else, but for tomorrow's me, fight!
楽するために苦しいことも　乗り越えちゃうんだからね　Fight
I'll even overcome hard things so I can take it easy later, fight!
やりたくないこと　やらないために　やりたくないこと　やれ　Fight
To avoid things you don't want to do, do the things you don't want to, fight!
あれ？これって結局　頑張れてる私　とってもえらいじゃないか　Fight
Huh? In the end, isn't me who's working hard really great? Fight!
自分時間　だらくタイム確保　5時9時を死守しますと
Secure my personal lazy time, I'll defend my 5-to-9
さらに愛や　恋や　甘いもん忘れずに　とどのつまり
Don't forget love, romance, and sweets, in short
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよ　手注意喚起もしてますよ
Overwork is strictly prohibited, I'm issuing a warning
ねえ楽して　上手くして　生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living life easily and doing it well is hard
だって安手　裏技　一夜漬け　甘い水には罠がある
Cheap tricks, shortcuts, cramming, sweet water has traps
Yeah!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleep when I'm sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Wake up past noon
遊びたきゃ遊ぶ
Play if I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eat when I'm hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laugh when I'm happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
If I'm sad, it's okay to cry, isn't it?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For tomorrow's me, I'll manage to do my best today
明日も頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
Working hard so I won't have to tomorrow
ハンパないっ ぱらっ ぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっ
It's unreal, pa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra
Hey 限界 突破らっ ぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっ
Hey, break through the limit, pa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra
Hey 毎日 ハンパないっ ぱらっ ぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっ
Hey, every day is unreal, pa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra
Hey 限界 突破らっ ぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっ
Hey, break through the limit, pa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra-ppa-ra
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent something
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Cancel your live bookings and invent something
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I'll become an inventor king like that
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent something
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Cancel your live bookings and invent something
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I'll become an inventor king like that
踊るエジソン　自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン　自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン　自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン　自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン　自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン　自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン　自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン　自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
幼少期の頃から家で聴いてた音楽はハウスミュージック
Since childhood, the music I listened to at home was house music
サブスクのプレイリスト聞いて曲ディグったならばクラブでDJ
I listened to sub playlists, and if I dug a track I'd DJ it at the club
パソコン開いたならDTM　ソフトはAbleton Live
If I open my PC it's DTM, the software is Ableton Live
エジソン
Edison
だけど今作りたいのは蓄音機
But what I want to make now is a gramophone
サークルでの宴会芸
A party trick in a circle
ノリで始めたバンドで
A band started on a whim
まぐれでバズって
Buzzing by chance
メジャーデビュー
and making a major debut
なぜか今はしがないミュージシャン
For some reason, I'm just a humble musician now
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン ジソンシン
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン ジソンシン
Singing Edison, self-esteem
Woo!
YouTubeを見て得る1%のひらめき
1% inspiration from watching YouTube
インスピレーション
Inspiration
SNS通して繋がる
Connecting through SNS
発明家とのコミュニケーション
Communication with inventors
インスタ映え狙った投稿
Posts aimed for Instagrammability
webニュースで情報収集
Gathering information via Web news
間違いなくこれから時代来るのは
Undoubtedly, the next big thing
活動写真
will be moving pictures
いや、絶対来ると思うんだけどなー
No, I really think it's coming...
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明してて
Kicking live bookings and keep inventing
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I will become the King of Inventors
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン ジソンシン
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン ジソンシン
Singing Edison, self-esteem
Woo!
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
It's not goodbye like this today
手をとってくれたなら
If you took my hand
ours (Acoustic & Piano ver)
作詞・作曲：古川本舗 編曲：古川本舗 / 和音正人
Lyrics/Comp: Furukawa Honpo. Arr: Furukawa Honpo / Waon Masato
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
On a night where even secrets fall asleep
君を連れていくよ
I'll take you with me
それは例えば遠く離れていたって
Even if, for example, we were far apart
手をつないでいられるような
Like we could keep holding hands
奇跡のような
Like a miracle
話をしようよ
Let's talk
窓は開けておいて
Keep the window open
今日までを思い出して
Thinking back on today
一つ一つ並べたら
If we line them up one by one
明日の雨が気になりだして
I started worrying about tomorrow's rain
どうも眠れないみたいだ
I guess I can't sleep
変わりたくないことや
Things I don't want to change
変わらなきゃいけないことも
And things that must change
少し忘れたまま
Leaving them a bit forgotten
窓の外を眺めていたんだ
I was looking out the window
ああ 雨が降り出すその前に
Ah, before the rain starts falling
君のところまで行けるような気がして
I feel like I can make it to where you are
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes
そしてこのまま遠くへと行こう
And let's go far away like this
手をとってくれるかな
Will you take my hand?
秘密も眠りにつくような夜を
A night where even secrets fall asleep
君とおよいでいくよ
I'll swim through it with you
街の明かりが消えるたびに笑って
Laughing every time the city lights go out
路地裏で抱き合おう
Let's embrace in a back alley
馬鹿みたいな
Like fools
話をしようよ
Let's talk
窓は開けておいて
Keep the window open
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや 無くせないものを
Dear things and things I can't lose
教えてくれたのは
What taught me that
今日みたいな夜を重ねて
was layering nights like today
織り上げてきた私たちに響く音
The sound that resonates within us, woven together
夜が来るたびに心が躍ってしまうのは
The reason my heart dances every time night comes
また一つ重なっていくから
Is because another one is being layered
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes.
今夜　私たちだけで眠ろう
Tonight, let's sleep just by ourselves.
誰にも言わないで
Don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつくその少し前に
Just a little before you fall asleep,
名前を呼んで
call my name.
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで
My heart aches for a wish that won't come true,
俯いてしまうけど
and I end up looking down, but
誰もいない街へ誘いに行くから
I'll go and invite you to a town where nobody is.
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
Today isn't a goodbye just like this.
手をとってくれたなら
If you take my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
in a night where even secrets seem to fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I'll take you away.
それは例えば遠く離れていたって
For example, even if we were far apart,
手を繋いでいられるような
so that we can keep holding hands,
奇跡のような話をしよう
let's talk about something like a miracle.
窓は開けておいて
Leave the window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや、なくせないものを
Lovely things and things we can't lose...
教えてくれたのは今日みたいな
What taught me those was a night like today,
夜を重ねて織り上げてきた
layered and woven together,
私たちに響く音
the sound that resonates with us.
はい！
Yes!
ということで、皆さん、今回のライブ、
So, everyone, for this live,
なんと新衣装がババババーンとありました！
I unexpectedly had a brand new outfit!
ということで、あの、びっくりしたかな？びっくりしたんじゃないかなと思います。
So, um, were you surprised? I think you must have been surprised.
あの、こちらね、すごい、あの、煌びやかな衣装となっているんですけど、
Um, this one is a really, um, gorgeous outfit,
ちょっと今、スクショタイム、撮る？
Should we have a screenshot time now?
イエーイ！
Yay!
可愛いですかー？
Is it cute?
ぜひ、あのハッシュタグでね、あのぜひ呟いてください。
Please, by all means, post with the hashtag.
可愛いでしょ？
It's cute, right?
何やらね、この後、ちょっと衣装のね、色々、あの細部までちょっと見る機会がありそうな予感がするので、
Somehow, I have a feeling there might be a chance to see various details of the outfit later,
一旦ね、スクショだけお願いします。
so for now, please just take screenshots.
そして、あとこちらね、見て！
And also, look at this!
手首に、プラプラーって紐があるんだけど、これね、取れます！
There are these dangling ribbons on my wrists, but you see, they're removable!
じゃあちょっと取ってもらおうかな。
Well then, let's have them taken off.
えい！
Hah!
ということで、はい、取れまーす！
So, yes, they come off!
こちらバージョンも、スクショ撮ってもらおう。
Let's have you take screenshots of this version too.
イエーイ！
Yay!
可愛いですかー？
Is it cute?
ね、すごい、可愛らしい衣装。
Right? It's a really lovely outfit.
えっちょっとね、あのドキドキするんですが。
Um, I'm a bit nervous though.
うーん。いやー、なんかでもちょっと一人寂しいな。
Hmm. Man, but somehow I feel a bit lonely being alone.
なんか、団員さん…うーん…
I wonder if the Danins... hmm...
あっ！だ、ダイ福くん！お、なんかモゾモゾしてる。おっどうしたどうしたどうした？
Ah! Dai- Daifuku-kun! Oh, he's squirming. Oh, what's wrong, what's wrong?
ぐわぁー！
Whoa!
ダイ福くん飛んできた！
Daifuku-kun came flying!
そんなに、え、ノエちゃんに会いたかったんかな？可愛いね。
Did you want to see Noe-chan that much? You're cute.
いっぱいスクショ撮れた？
Did you get plenty of screenshots?
うん。ダイ福くんとのツーショット。可愛い。えっなになに？
Yeah. A two-shot with Daifuku-kun. Cute. Oh, what's this?
あ、今日は安眠テーマで、あ、心地が良い。あ、なるほどね。ん？
Ah, since today's theme is "peaceful sleep," ah, it feels good. Ah, I see. Hm?
曲のリクエスト？あ、子守唄みたいな曲が聴きたい。あ、そうなの？ダイ福くん。
A song request? Ah, you want to hear a song like a lullaby. Oh, is that so? Daifuku-kun.
じゃあせっかくね、ダイ福くん来てくれたし、一緒にじゃあ子守唄、うん。
Well then, since Daifuku-kun is here, let's sing a lullaby together, yeah.
歌うよ、歌う。だからちょっとついてきて。一緒に行くよ。おらおらーい！
I'll sing, I'll sing. So come along for a bit. We're going together. Here we go!
小さな人の子よ
O little child of man,
森へ迷い込んだ
you've wandered into the forest.
大きな次の…
Into the large next...
金の羽が 坊やは見えないのね
The golden wings, the boy cannot see them, can he?
何も知らない まあるいほっぺよ
Knowing nothing, those round cheeks...
眠れや 眠れ
Sleep, sleep...
静かな 水辺においで
Come to the quiet waterside...
坊やの夢は
The boy's dream is...
竜の背に 運ばれて
Carried on a dragon's back...
山の向こうへ 消える
Disappearing beyond the mountains.
よろずの子らも
All the children...
並んで眠る
Sleep side-by-side.
七つ数えたら
If you count to seven...
仲良く眠ってゆく
They all fall asleep together.
何も見えない
Seeing nothing...
小さなおめめよ
Those tiny eyes...
眠れや 眠れ
Sleep, sleep...
そよぐ 草むらおいで
Come to the rustling grass...
坊やの夢は
The boy's dream is...
母さんを 探しては
Searching for mother...
空の向こうへ 帰る
Returning beyond the sky.
竜の背に 運ばれて
Carried on a dragon's back...
山の向こうへ 消える
Disappearing beyond the mountains.
プラネタリウム
Planetarium
夕月夜 顔だす
The evening moon appears,
消えてく 子供の声
and the voices of children fade away.
遠く 遠く
Far, far away,
この空の どこかに君はいるんだろう
somewhere in this sky, you must be there.
夏の終わりに 2人で
At the end of summer, we two
抜け出した この公園で
slipped away into this park.
見つけた あの星座
We found that constellation,
何だか 覚えてる
I somehow remember it.
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I'll trace my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness.
あの香りと ともに
Along with that scent,
花火が ぱっと開く
the fireworks suddenly burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are,
今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to start running and go to you right now.
まっ暗で 何も見えない
It's pitch black and I can't see anything,
怖くても 大丈夫
but even if I'm scared, I'll be okay.
数えきれない 星空が
The countless stars in the sky
今も ずっと ここにあるんだよ
are still here, and they always will be.
泣かないよ...
I won't cry...
一緒に見た 綺麗な空だったから
Because it was the beautiful sky we saw together
あの道まで響く 靴の音が耳に残る
The sound of shoes echoing to that path remains in my ears
大きな自分の影を 見つめて想うのでしょう
I guess I'm thinking while staring at my large shadow
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに
Even though it shouldn't have changed a bit
せつない気持ち膨らんでく
This painful feeling keeps swelling up
どんなに想ったって 君はもういない
No matter how much I think of you, you're no longer here
行きたいよ 君のそばに
I want to go to your side
小さくても 小さくても
Even if I'm small, even if I'm small
一番に 君が好きだよ
I love you the most
強くいられる
I can be strong
願いを 流れ星に
A wish upon a shooting star
そっと 唱えてみたけれど
I tried chanting it softly, but...
泣かないよ 届くだろう
I won't cry, it'll reach you, right?
綺麗な空に
In the beautiful sky
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I'll trace my memories
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness
あの香りと共に
Along with that scent
花火がパッと開く
Fireworks suddenly burst open
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are
小さな手を握りしめて
Clutching your small hand
泣きたいよ それはそれは
I want to cry, it was so, so...
綺麗な空だった
A beautiful sky
願いを 流れ星に
A wish upon a shooting star
そっと 唱えてみたけれど
I tried chanting it softly, but...
泣きたいよ 届かない想いを
I want to cry, these feelings that won't reach
この空に...
to this sky...
もう何十回 もう何百回も 震むソラ見上げて
Dozens of times, hundreds of times, looking up at the shaking sky
辿り着いた場所が 運命のダイヤモンド
The place I arrived at is the diamond of fate
何千回 もう何万回も 涙流したきみへ
To you, who has shed tears thousands, even tens of thousands of times
ねえ 諦められたことはあったっけ？
Hey, was there anything you could ever give up on?
「憧れ＝限界」だから もういらないよ
Since 'Admiration = Limit', I don't need it anymore
そこに留まるなんて もったいないでしょ
Staying there would be a waste, wouldn't it?
それぞれの物語 交差する瞬間を
The moment where each of our stories intersect
見つめる意味は
The meaning of gazing at it is
放った夢だけ 大きな弧を描いて
Only the dreams released will draw a large arc
はじきれそうな 煌めきを
A radiance that seems about to burst
消えることなく どこまででも
Without fading away, no matter how far
世界の向こうに 届けよう
Let's reach out to the other side of the world
終わることのない この胸の衝動は
This impulse in my heart that never ends
どうしたって どうしても ぼくを呼んでいた
No matter what, it was calling out to me
だから その先へと
So, towards what lies ahead
走り続ける
I'll keep on running
次へ 次へ
To the next, to the next
夢想だった 中途半端な 凱歌抱えて 立ち尽くしていた
Clutching a half-baked victory song that was but a dream, I stood still
通り雨はプレリュード 何千回 もう何万回も
The passing shower is a prelude, thousands, tens of thousands of times
挑み続けたきみへ ねえ聴かせてよ
To you who kept on challenging, hey, let me hear it
「夢は叶った」って
Saying "dreams came true"
「諦め＝完敗」ならば 絶対にないよ
If "giving up = complete defeat," then that'll never happen
だれに邪魔されようと ためらわないで
No matter who tries to stop you, don't hesitate
託された情熱を 落とさずにつないでいく
Passing on the passion entrusted to me without letting it drop
そう 最後まで
Yes, until the very end
フラッグに誓い 勇ましく旗めいて
Swearing on the flag, fluttering bravely
鳴り止まないファンファーレ
The fanfare that never stops ringing
いつも心に 流れていた
It was always flowing in my heart
遠い未来へ 祈るよう
Like a prayer to the distant future
忘れられない あの日々の後悔を
The regrets of those unforgettable days
追いかけて 追いかけて 滑り込んだ
Chasing, chasing, I slipped into...
この想い
This feeling
青いソラに ふと溢れていった
Suddenly overflowed into the blue sky
遠く 遠く
Far away, far away
トレビアンナイト
Tres Bien Night
終わらない 終わらない 仕事が山積み終わらない
Never ending, never ending, work is piled up and never ending
止まらない 止まらない それでも時間は止まらない
Won't stop, won't stop, even so, time won't stop
Yo, Yo!
Hate to Hate 溜まり溜まった Hate
Hate to Hate, the accumulated hate
伝播と自壊バット 本望滅する金属バット
Propagation and self-destruction bat, metal bat that destroys true desires
Swing! 今日も一杯 今日も一杯
Swing! Another cup today, another cup today
Wow! No more 鞭 Gimmie Gimmie juicy
Wow! No more whip, give me give me juicy
I see 奔走 Anytime 奔走 Anytime
I see, rushing anytime, rushing anytime
はあー 溜息プレッシャーでエネルギーすっからかん
Phew... Energy is empty from the pressure of sighs
よいしょー！ 自分自身に厳しすぎちゃう
Heave-ho! I'm being way too hard on myself
すぐさまヘラヘラ優等生 さっぱり足りない順応性
Instantly a smiling honor student, completely lacking adaptability
自分自身としっかり向き合う
Facing myself properly
一番必要なものは
The thing I need the most...
トレビアン ご褒美 頂戴
Is a "Tres Bien" reward, please give it to me
Wah! てんてこ舞いようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Wah! Say bye-bye to this hectic rhythm
ドレミファ の音にご覧
Look at the Do-Re-Mi notes
Wow! ぎゅーっと詰めちゃダメ どんどんフリーダム
Wow! Don't cram it in too tight, more and more freedom
Oh... オーライ オーライ
Oh... Alright, alright
好きなもの食べ放題 オキシトシン増します脳内
All-you-can-eat favorite things, oxytocin increases in my brain
ほら もっともっと頂戴 膨大
Look, give me more and more, huge amount
Get ready! サボりです たまに空振り
Get ready! I'm slacking off, occasionally swinging and missing
見した彦星 胸張りお祭り
Showing off the Hikoboshi, chest out at the festival
いらない まやかしの甘い夜更かし
Don't need it, the sweet staying up late of fake deception
ハッピーになるため歌おう 声高らかに
Let's sing to be happy, voices loud and clear
自分自身がやっぱり一番
After all, I myself am number one
理性と欲望が平行線 望みは幸せエンドレス
Reason and desire are parallel lines, my wish is endless happiness
自分自身としっかり付き合う
Getting along properly with myself
我慢は体に毒だよ
Patience is poison to the body
トレビアン ご褒美 頂戴
Is a "Tres Bien" reward, please give it to me
Wah! てんてこ舞いようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Wah! Say bye-bye to this hectic rhythm
ドレミファ の音にご覧
Look at the Do-Re-Mi notes
Wah! ぎゅーっと詰めちゃダメ どんどんフリーダム
Wah! Don't cram it in too tight, more and more freedom
一、二の三 はい！
One, two, three, go!
窮屈な靴に 疲弊やすストレス
Getting tired of cramped shoes, easy stress
状態 状況 から解放
Release from states and situations
もっともっともっともっとまだまだ足りない
More, more, more, more, it's still not enough!
本日は欲望解放パーティーナイト！
Today is the desire-release party night!
乾杯！
Cheers!
トレビアン 暴動 美を頂戴
Trés bien, give me that riotous beauty
てんてこ舞いようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say goodbye to a rhythm that's like a frantic dance
トレビアン 暴動 美をご来
Trés bien, witness that riotous beauty
ぎゅうぎゅうと詰めちゃダメどんどん振り出そう
Don't pack it in tight, let's keep pouring it out
ぎゅぎゅっと夢のご褒美どんどん好きになる
A tightly packed reward of dreams, I like it more and more
フィーバー！
Fever!
輝夜の城で踊りたい
I want to dance at Kaguya's castle
おいで！おいで！誘惑のDance again
Come on! Come on! Temptation's Dance again
おいで！おいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on! Come on! To Kaguya's castle
出逢いがあやつるミステリー
A mystery manipulated by encounters
危険なペルソナ
A dangerous persona
踊ろう！踊ろう！終わらないDance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! Unending Dance beat
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! At Kaguya's castle
夜空を切り取るレーザービーム
Laser beams cutting through the night sky
私と見てよ？
Look at me, okay?
まばゆい星が照らす想い
Feelings illuminated by dazzling stars
今宵の夢よ永遠に
May tonight's dream last forever
明日のことは忘れたいの
I want to forget about tomorrow
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of the red rose
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be gently swept away
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly to me
意味ありげに目をそらす
Meaningfully averting my eyes
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the knight of the white moon
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched me is still hot
のがさずに抱きしめて
Don't let go, hold me tight
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
This miracle is called love, isn't it?
おいで！おいで！情熱でDance again
Come on! Come on! With passion, Dance again
おいで！おいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on! Come on! To Kaguya's castle
迷いを飲み込むエナジー
Energy that swallows hesitation
眠らぬパッショネイト
Sleepless Passionate
踊ろう！踊ろう！止まらないDance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! Unstoppable Dance beat
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! At Kaguya's castle
星座が織りなすディスコティーク
A discotheque woven by the constellations
私も混ぜて？
Can I join too?
きらめく星に誓う心
A heart vowing to the twinkling stars
儚い夢でいいわ
A fleeting dream is fine
明日は明日の風が吹くの
Tomorrow is another day
だよね！
Right!
私は黒い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of the black rose
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be intensely swept away
だから微笑んで
So, give me a smile
追いかけてと瞳が誘う
My eyes invite you to chase me
あなたも黒い月の騎士
You too are the knight of the black moon
瞳の奥は熱い
The depths of your eyes are hot
つかまえて抱きしめて
Catch me and hold me tight
この奇跡は恋を呼ぶのね
This miracle calls for love, doesn't it?
一緒に行こう！
Let's go together!
ついてきてよ！
Follow me!
他の人を見ちゃヤダ！
Don't look at anyone else!
私だけを見て！
Look only at me!
後悔するわよ！
You'll regret it!
楽しもう！
Let's have fun!
早くしなさいよ！
Hurry up!
鈍いのですね...
You're slow, aren't you...
いいの？
Is it okay?
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of the red rose
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be gently swept away
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly to me
意味ありげに目をそらす
Meaningfully averting my eyes
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the knight of the white moon
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched me is still hot
のがさずに抱きしめて
Don't let go, hold me tight
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
This miracle is called love, isn't it?
はっ！
Ha!
うふっ！
Uh-huh!
はーっ！
Ha!
というわけで、三期生の皆と「輝夜の城で踊りたい」を歌って踊りましたー！
And so, I sang and danced to "Kaguya no Shiro de Odoritai" with the rest of the 3rd Generation!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ノエルちゃん、お誕生日...
Noel-chan, happy...
おめでとうー！
Birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ちょっと可愛いんじゃない？
Aren't you a bit cute?
はい、可愛い？
Yes, am I cute?
ちょっと服装に対して動きが... 動きがちょっと...
Wait, your movements for that outfit... your movements are a bit...
動きがちょっとね、あ、ちょっとお淑やかに...
My movements are a bit... ah, let's be a bit more ladylike...
はい、可愛くしてもらって...
Yes, please be cute...
可愛い～
Cute~
すごいね、なんかここがね...
Wow, like, this part here...
ね、思う。ここ大丈夫ですか？
Right? I think so too. Is this part okay?
おっぱいがお尻だよ、ノエルちゃん！
Your breasts are like butts, Noel-chan!
女の子のおっぱいに挨拶しちゃう！
I'm gonna greet a girl's breasts!
やだ～、でもこっちからはさ、こう話せばいいのかな？
No way~ But from here, is it okay to talk like this?
違う違う違う... あ、あ、ちょっと...
No, no, no... ah, wait a bit...
えっと、今回のね衣装はね、あの200万人の記念で、はい、作っていただきました。
Um, this outfit was made to celebrate reaching 2 million subscribers.
他にも変わったところ、今日のあのライブからであるんだけど...
There are other things that have changed starting with today's live...
どこ変わった？
What's different?
あれ？マリンが怒ってる？
Huh? Is Marine angry?
え？どこ変わった？
Eh? What changed?
あ、キャー！
Ah, kyaa!
え、気づいた？ということで...
Eh, did you notice? So...
当たり前だろ！
Of course I did!
そうなんですよ。ちょっとメイク変わりました。え、大丈夫？
That's right. My makeup changed a bit. Is it okay?
全然違うじゃん！すごい可愛い！
It's totally different! It's so cute!
ちなみに、お気に入りの顔がありまして、ちょっとね、あの、お困り顔。
By the way, I have a favorite face, which is my "troubled face."
お困り顔がね、そう、可愛いんです。
The troubled face is really cute.
お口がね、ちょっと「ぷりっ」てなってるんです。
The mouth is a bit like a pout.
あ、本当だ、こだわりだね！
Ah, you're right, that's a nice detail!
食べちゃうぞ～！
I'm gonna eat you up!
うわ～、えぐい... うわ、じゃなかった。
Uwaa, gross... wait, I shouldn't say that.
え、じゃあちょっと衣装、せっかくなんで...
Well, since it's a special occasion, let's look at the outfit...
下から、下からちょっと舐めるように行きましょうよ。
Let's go from the bottom, looking it over slowly.
靴から見ましょう、靴から。
Let's look at the shoes, starting with the shoes.
おら、可愛い～
Look, so cute~
お靴いいでしょ、ちょっとよく見せて。あ、ヒールなのね！
The shoes are nice, let us see them better. Oh, they're heels!
可愛い～
Cute~
リボンついてて。
They have ribbons.
普段はね、通常でぺったんこだから、ちょっと身長盛りました。
Usually, they're flat, so I added some height.
リボン2個構え、後ろにね！
Two ribbons, on the back too!
そうなんです。ついてます。
That's right. They're there.
いい、いい、いい。じゃあちょっと舐めるように... お、お、お...
Good, good, good. Now, looking it over slowly... Oh, oh, oh...
一体どんなおぱんつ... あ、怒られた！
I wonder what kind of panties... Ah, she got mad!
何変態... 好奇心が...
What a pervert... My curiosity...
え、こんな感じで、リボンが...
Um, like this, the ribbons...
ちょっとそんなササッと終わんないで！まだ舐めてる最中だから！まだ舐めてる最中！
Wait, don't end it so quickly! We're still in the middle of looking! Still looking!
あ～！あ～！あ～！
Aaah! Aaah! Aaah!
ここね、あのエヌエルがいてね...
Here, there's the "NL" logo...
あ、ノエルじゃなくて...
Ah, not Noel, but...
ノエルちゃんじゃなくて、ここ！皆さんご覧ください！
Not Noel-chan, but here! Everyone, please look!
ここの、この、この、この、この、胸の、この、ここ！この隙間、隙間、隙間！
Here, this, this, this, this, on the chest, this, here! This gap, gap, gap!
分かります？この下乳との間の隙間！
Do you see? This gap between her underboob!
本当だ、すごいね。このあたり。隙間がね、ほら！
You're right, that's amazing. Around here. The gap, look!
うわ～！大丈夫、ぺこら、大丈夫！
Uwaaa! It's okay, Pekora, it's okay!
ね、最高。衣装。
Right, it's the best. The outfit.
じゃあちょっと上見せるにあたって、このね、ヒラヒラ取れるから...
Well, to show the upper part, this frilly part can be removed, so...
ちょっと、ちょっと取ってもいい？
Can I take it off for a bit?
取ってみて、取ってみて！
Try taking it off, try it!
はい、取ってください。お、おお～！
Yes, please take it off. Oh, ooh~!
脱ぎやすい。万歳！
It's easy to take off. Banzai!
え、横はどうなってるのかしら。ゆっくりくるくる回って。
Oh, I wonder what the sides look like. Turn around slowly.
くるくるくるくる...
Spin, spin, spin, spin...
あ、可愛い～！髪の毛フワフワで可愛い！
Ah, cute~! Her hair is so fluffy and cute!
ありがとうございます。髪型もちょっと...
Thank you very much. The hairstyle is also a bit...
お姫様みたい！あ、すごいリボンがこう、髪にね、こう巻き込んである感じで。
Like a princess! Oh, wow, the ribbons are like, woven into the hair.
そうなんです。編み込んで。
That's right. It's braided in.
え、ぺこらちゃんも言ってましたけど、さあ、姫騎士なんでね、お姫様、なってます。
As Pekora-chan said, since I'm a Knight Princess, I've become a princess.
可愛すぎる。こんなの好きになっちゃう。
Too cute. I'm falling for this.
ちょっと変える、化したいから、ちょっといつもの動きして。
I want to see her transform back, so do your usual movements for a bit.
待ってた、待ってた！
I was waiting for that, waiting!
あ、なんか好きじゃなくなった。
Ah, I don't like it anymore.
あ、危ない危ない！恋するところだった。
Ah, that was close! I was about to fall in love.
いやでも本当に可愛い衣装...
But really, it's such a cute outfit...
ありがとう、おめでとう。いいかも、マジで超可愛い。
Thank you, congratulations. It might be good, seriously super cute.
いやでもさ、皆さん。今回はね、その団長の衣装、新衣装お披露目だったから...
But you know, everyone. This time was for the Commander's new outfit reveal...
皆にはちょっとアイドル衣装だったんですけど...
So everyone else was in their idol outfits, but...
そう、え、皆もさ、衣装持ってるじゃん。
Right, and you guys have new outfits too, right?
あ、そう、並んだりとかも今後したいな。
Ah, right, I'd like to line up together in the future.
え、絶対やろう！並ぼう並ぼう！
Let's definitely do it! Let's line up together!
てか3Dでまた歌って踊りたいな！
Actually, I want to sing and dance in 3D again!
え、ちょっとそれ！え、マジで？
Wait, that! Eh, really?
そんなお話あったかな？
Was there such a talk?
はい！ということで、ここから大事なお知らせをたくさんしていきます！
Yes! So, from here on, I'll be making many important announcements!
まず、ホロライブ3期生の単独ライブ！
First, a hololive 3rd Generation solo live!
「hololive 3rd Generation Live きめるるん大作戦 最強アイドル、推ししかないでしょう」開催決定しております！
"hololive 3rd Generation Live: Kimerurun Great Strategy - The Strongest Idols, You've No Choice but to Stan" has been confirmed!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい。え、日時ですが、2026年1月の17日と...
Yes. As for the dates, they're January 17th, 2026, and...
18日の2日間にわたって開催されます。
18th, held over two days.
会場はね、あのデカい、そう、Kアリーナ横浜となってます！
The venue is that huge one, yes, K-Arena Yokohama!
昨日ね、なんと、ちょっと二次先行、ちょうどね、終わったところなんですけど...
Actually, as of yesterday, the second round of advance tickets just finished, but...
なんかね、この後、ま、先着の一般販売が、12月の14日とかのお昼の12時から...
It seems that after this, the first-come-first-served general sales will start on December 14th from noon...
まだ間に合う、まだまだ諦めずに
There's still time, so don't give up yet.
当てるチャンス大変だと思うけど、ぜひぜひあの勝ち取ってください。
I know it's a tough chance to win, but please, please do your best to get it.
お願いしまーす！
Please!
そして配信チケットはね、まだありますので、はい。
And as for streaming tickets, they're still available, yes.
絶賛発売中ですので、よろしくお願いいたします。
They are now on sale, so we appreciate your support.
お願いしまーす！
Please!
そして、まあこのライブを見てくださった方で、まあ買い忘れてる人はいないと思うけど、
And for those of you watching this live, I'm sure no one has forgotten to buy them, but...
あのグッズのね、先行販売と受注販売も明日のね、えー、11月25日の
The pre-sales and made-to-order sales for the merchandise are available until tomorrow,
18時までとなっております。
November 25th, at 6:00 PM.
明日ね！ そう！
Tomorrow! Right!
だから、あのライブ会場でペンライト振りたいとか、
So, if you want to wave a penlight at the live venue,
配信見ながらペンライト振りたいよって人はぜひ、えーこの機会をお見逃しなく！
Or if you want to wave one while watching the stream, don't miss this chance!
現地行く人はぜひとも絶対絶対あったほうが盛り上がりますよ！
If you're going in person, you'll definitely have more fun if you have one!
お願いしまーす！
Please!
いやー楽しみだね。
I'm really looking forward to it.
めっちゃ楽しみ！
So excited!
そう、団長もね、ちょっとおめめを変えたから。
Yes, and I've updated my look a bit as well.
かわいいー！ 楽しみー！
So cute! Can't wait!
そんな感じで、せっかくね来てくれたから、意気込みを一言ちょっと一言ずつ聞こうかな。
Since you're here, I'd like to hear a brief word of enthusiasm from each of you.
一言ね。
A quick word, okay.
任せろー！ 誰から行く？
Leave it to me! Who's going first?
やる気いっぱいだぜ！
I'm all fired up!
えーじゃあちょっとマリンから、こういう順番で、マリン、すごい良いこと言ってくれるんだろうな。
Okay, let's start with Marine and go in this order. I'm sure Marine will say something great.
頑張るぞー！
I'll do my best!
楽しむぞー！
I'm going to have fun!
みんなで盛り上げるぞー！
Let's all get hyped up together!
おー、ありがとう。え、え、なになに？あ、あ、あ、
Oh, thank you. Wait, what? Oh, oh...
光の速さで去っていった...みんなありがとう！
They left at the speed of light... thank you, everyone!
てな感じで、えーここからはノエちゃんの告知に行きます！
And with that, I'll move on to some announcements from Noe-chan!
えーまず一つ目はこちら！
First, here's the first one!
はい、今年も出ます。白銀ノエル誕生日記念2025のグッズ、わーい！
Yes, they're coming out again this year. Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025 merchandise, yay!
えー生誕グッズ、まずはこちら！
Birthday merch, first up is this!
はい、えー「睡夢の世界へ」キラキラLEDアートパネル。イラストはMyungYi先生が...
Yes, the 'To the World of Dreams' Sparkling LED Art Panel. The illustration was...
...描いてくれました。ありがとうございます。いつもお世話になってます。らぶちらぶち。
...drawn by MyungYi-sensei. Thank you very much. I'm always in your debt. Love you, love you.
今回のね、生誕ライブのステージと新衣装がテーマになっております。
The theme is the stage and new outfit from this birthday live.
まあLEDということで、こちら光るということでね、ぜひお部屋に飾って、
Since it's LED, it glows, so please display it in your room,
あの今回のライブを思い出して、そう思い出にしてください。はい。
and use it to remember this live. Yes.
そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
はい、「色んなノエちゃん」ランダムマルチバンド、ということで、まえり先生が描いてくれました。ありがとうございます。
Yes, the 'Various Noe-chans' Random Multi-bands, drawn by Maeri-sensei. Thank you very much.
いや色んなね、ノエちゃんがいますので、まあちょっとどのノエちゃんがね、お家に来るかなーってちょっと楽しみにしつつ、
There are many different Noe-chans, so look forward to seeing which one comes to your home,
届いたらね、まあマルチバンド、こちら、あのお片付けの必需品となってます。
and once they arrive, these multi-bands are essential for organizing.
ノエちゃんも使っておりますので、ぜひね、あのコードまとめる時とか、はい実用性に富んでますので、使ってみてください。
I use them too, and they're very practical for things like bundling cords, so please give them a try.
次はこちら！
Next is this!
はい、姫騎士ノエルぬいぐるみキーホルダーということで、昨年はね、あのサンタさんのノエちゃんがぬいぐるみとしてキーホルダー出たんですが、
Yes, the Princess Knight Noel Plushie Keychain. Last year, we had a plushie keychain of Santa Noe-chan,
今回はせっかく新衣装が出たので、こちらでぬいぐるみキーホルダーを作りました。
but since we have a new outfit this time, we made a plushie keychain of it.
あの姫騎士として団員さんを守りますので、ぜひ肌身離さず持ってください。
I'll protect the Knight Brats as a princess knight, so please keep it with you at all times.
次はこちら！
Next is this!
はい、わんちょむ2wayネックピローということで、安眠に最適なネックピローなんですけど、
Yes, the Wanchom 2way Neck Pillow. It's a neck pillow perfect for a good night's sleep,
今回はなんと、ひっくり返すとわんちょむになっているということで、
but this time, if you flip it inside out, it turns into Wanchom!
まあわんちょむはね、今年から団長のお家にお迎えしたワンちゃんのことなんですけど、グッズにしちゃいました。
Wanchom is the name of the dog I welcomed into my home this year, and I've made him into merch.
え、ちょっとね、ノエちゃんの愛、私情が入ってますということで、ぜひ団員さんのお家にも迎えてください。
A bit of my personal love went into this, so please welcome him into your home as well.
最後にフルセットを見てみましょう。こちら！
Finally, let's look at the full set. This one!
はい、今年もいっぱい、いっぱいグッズが出ました。いやぜひぜひゲットしてみてね。
Yes, a lot of merchandise is coming out again this year. Please be sure to get yours.
そしてこの全部のフルセット特典があります。それはこちら！
And there's a bonus for the full set. This one!
はい、ということでフルセットを購入してくださった方に、チェキ風ブロマイドカード付いてきます！
Yes, for those who purchase the full set, you'll get a polaroid-style bromide card!
いやとても素敵。まあイラストはね、MyungYi先生のイラストで、こちらに、えーと...
It's so lovely. The illustration is by MyungYi-sensei, and on this...
...通常バージョンは箔押しの複製サインが、ぺたってなるんですけど、
...the standard version has a foil-stamped replica signature,
数量限定バージョンは団長の直筆サインが付いてきます。
but the quantity limited version comes with my actual handwritten signature.
あの心を込めて書きますので、ぜひゲットしてみてください。
I'll write it with all my heart, so please try to get one.
さらにね、さらにさらに、フルセットを購入してくれた方全員に、特典ボイスも付いてきちゃいます！
And there's even more, everyone who buys the full set will also receive a bonus voice!
フルセットのね、なんかちょっと欲しいって、みんな思ったんじゃないでしょうか。ぜひゲットしてみてください。
I'm sure you're all thinking you want the full set now. Please check it out.
ボイスもね。
The voice too.
心込めて撮ります！
I'll take it with all my heart!
よろしくお願いしますー！えー、
Please look forward to it! Um,
生誕グッズは22時カートオープンです！
the birthday goods cart opens at 22:00!
皆さん、ぜひゲットしてください！
Everyone, please make sure to get them!
お願いいたしまーす！
Thank you very much!
さらにさらに、重大告知があります！
And more, and more, I have a huge announcement!
なんとそれは...（ドラムロール）
And that is... [drumroll]
はい！新曲がありますー！
Yes! I have a new song!
で、その新曲を発表するにあたって、なんと！
And to announce that new song, surprisingly!
今回ちょっとスペシャルな方からね、コメントちょっといただいてるみたいなんだけど、
It seems we've received a comment from a very special person this time,
え、誰なんだろう？ちょっとノエルちゃんわかんないなー。誰でしょうか？
Wait, who could it be? I have no idea. Who is it?
え、待って！うわ、すごいキラキラしてる！
Wait! Whoa, it's so sparkly!
こんまっするー！
Konmassuru-!
白銀ノエルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Shirogane Noel-san, happy birthday!
そして団員の皆さん、配信を楽しんでいらっしゃいますか？
And to all the Knight Brats, are you enjoying the stream?
大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎です。
I'm Kiichiro Sato, the Governor of Oita Prefecture.
大分県応援団長 めじろんです！
I'm Mejiron, the leader of the Oita Prefecture cheer squad!
この度は新曲の発表もおめでとうございます。
Congratulations on the announcement of your new song.
今回、わたくしがノエルさんの新曲のタイトル発表を任せていただけることになりました。
This time, I have been entrusted with announcing the title of Noel-san's new song.
え！来てくれるんですか！
What! You're actually doing it!
それでは早速曲名を発表したいと思います。
Now, I'd like to announce the song title right away.
その名も...
The name is...
VAVAVA! バーチャル大分
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita
バーチャル大分！わーい！
Virtual Oita! Yay!
そうですね、『バーチャル大分』と入っていますので、大分をバーチャルで楽しめるような歌なのかな。
That's right, since it's titled 'Virtual Oita', I suppose it's a song where you can enjoy Oita virtually.
はい！そうです！
Yes! That's right!
はい！大分のオススメ沢山ありますよ！
Yes! There are many recommendations for Oita!
まずは何と言っても温泉です！
First and foremost, it's the hot springs!
大分県は源泉数、湧出量ともに全国一位ですから。
Oita Prefecture is number one in Japan for both the number of hot spring sources and the volume of discharge.
他にも、関アジや関サバ、かぼすブリ、おおいた和牛、唐揚げなんかの食の魅力も満載ですね。
There's also plenty of food appeal, like Seki-aji, Seki-saba, Kabosu Buri, Oita Wagyu, and Karaage.
ぜひ、皆さんにも味わっていただきたいです！
I'd really love for everyone to taste them!
はい！
Yes!
ノエルさん！大分を代表して応援しちょんけん！
Noel-san! I'm supporting you as a representative of Oita!
これからも大分県のPRを頼むけんね！
I'm counting on you to continue promoting Oita Prefecture!
新曲、真剣楽しみにしちょんけん！
I'm seriously looking forward to the new song!
それでは、おつまーするー！
Now then, Otsumassuru-!
あ、おつまーする！おつまーする！
Ah, Otsumassuru! Otsumassuru!
ということで、まさかの意外や意外、大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎さんに、
So, quite unexpectedly, we received from the Governor of Oita Prefecture, Kiichiro Sato-san,
新曲のタイトル発表と応援のコメントをいただきました。
the title announcement for the new song and a message of support.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
あの、これ本当にね、ノエルちゃんびっくりで、本当にこれサプライズなんですけど、
Um, I was really surprised by this, it truly was a surprise.
いや、本当にありがとうございます。
No, really, thank you very much.
まさかこんな日が来るなんてということで、
I never thought a day like this would come...
いや本当にすごい方からね、応援していただいて嬉しいですね。
I'm so happy to receive support from such an amazing person.
団長、何が起こったのか最初わからず、しかもめじろんも横にいて、あのね、緑の、そう、いましたね。
I didn't know what was happening at first, and Mejiron was there beside him too... that green one, yeah, it was there.
すごい可愛かったなと思います。
I thought it was so cute.
あの、本当にね、ずっと団長大分育ちで、はい、
Actually, I was raised in Oita, so,
大分の魅力をばーっと配信でね、個人的に言ってるだけなんですけど、
I've just been talking about the charms of Oita on my streams personally,
いや本当に日頃大分の魅力を伝えてきてよかったなと思います。
but I'm really glad I've been sharing how great Oita is every day.
あの、もちろんこれからも、個人的、特に何か大きなことがあるわけではなく、
Of course, from now on too, personally—not because of any big deal,
個人的に、はい、団長大分の魅力を伝えていきたいなと思いますので、
but just personally—I want to keep sharing Oita's charms,
皆さんもまだ大分に行ったことない人は、ぜひ大分行ってみてください。いいところだよ！
so if you haven't been to Oita yet, please go visit. It's a great place!
はい！ということで、新曲歌っちゃいたいと思います！
Alright! With that, I'd like to sing the new song!
聴いてください！『VAVAVA! バーチャル大分』！
Please listen to: 'VAVAVA! Virtual Oita'!
説明しよう。バーチャル大分とは、バーチャル九州の北東部に位置する広大な大地。現実の大分県に限りなく近い地上の楽園。人はその地を、バーチャル大分と呼ぶ。
Let me explain. Virtual Oita is a vast land located in the northeastern part of Virtual Kyushu. A paradise on earth extremely close to the real Oita Prefecture. People call that place, Virtual Oita.
ババババーチャル大分　世に放つ　ババババーチャル大分　湯を沸かす
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, releasing to the world. Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, boiling the water.
君とバーチャル大分　駆け巡る　ババババーチャル大分　大分どーん！
Running through Virtual Oita with you. Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
君は降り立つ　魅惑の地獄の入り口　絶えず湯沸く　誘惑の地
You land at the entrance of the enchanting Hells. A place of temptation where the water is always boiling.
海地獄　かまど　白池　血の池　鬼石坊主　鬼山　竜巻　ドーン！
Umi Jigoku, Kamado, Shiraike, Chinoike, Onishi Bozu, Oniyama, Tatsumaki, boom!
とり天　とりめし　やせうま　だんご汁　中津からあげ　冷麺　関アジ　関サバ
Toriten, Torimeshi, Yaseuma, Dango-jiru, Nakatsu Karaage, Reimen, Seki-aji, Seki-saba.
かぼす　あつめし　まだまだ入るよ　鉄の胃袋　大魔神
Kabosu, Atsumeshi, still more room inside. Iron stomach, Great Demon God.
行こうぜ久住高原　湯煙の温泉
Let's go to Kuju Highlands, hot springs of steam.
高崎山に
At Mt. Takasaki
金鱗湖
Lake Kinrin
青の洞門
Ao no Domon
由布川峡谷
Yufugawa Gorge
進め
Forward!
稲積水中鍾乳洞
Inazumi Underwater Cave
果てしなき旅
An endless journey
独歩遠足
Walking excursion
たどり着く先 食べる弁当
Eating a bento at the destination
時空を超えた奇跡の大地
A miraculous land across space-time
バーチャル大分 行くぞー！
Virtual Oita, here we go!
ババババーチャル大分 世に放つ
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, unleash it to the world
ババババーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, boil the water
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running through Virtual Oita with you
ババババーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, unleash it to the world
ババババーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, eat it all up
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running through Virtual Oita with you
ババババーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
大分どーん！
Oita boom!
よだきい
Lazy
しゃあしい
Annoying
えらしい
Lovely
しんけん
Serious
しやあねえ
Can't be helped
ふうがわりい
Strange
なしか
Why?
むげねえ
Heartbreaking
せせろしい
Noisy
だけどあんた
But you,
いまなにしちょん
what are you doing now?
説明しよう。
Let me explain.
バーチャル大分観光大使とは、バーチャル大分への深い郷土愛を持ち、
A Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador is someone who has a deep love for Virtual Oita,
その魅力を余すところなく伝え続ける存在。
and continues to convey its charm without reservation.
人はその大使の名を…
People call that ambassador...
バーチャル大分観光大使と呼ぶ！
the Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador!
バーチャル O-O-I-T-A
Virtual O-O-I-T-A
I wanna be 団長！ 団長！ 観光大使！
I wanna be Leader! Leader! Tourism Ambassador!
バーチャル O-O-I-T-A
Virtual O-O-I-T-A
団長！ 団長！ 観光大使（自称）
Leader! Leader! Tourism Ambassador (Self-proclaimed)
ババババーチャル大分 世に放つ
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, unleash it to the world
ババババーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, boil the water
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running through Virtual Oita with you
ババババーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, unleash it to the world
ババババーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, eat it all up
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running through Virtual Oita with you
ババババーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Va-va-va-Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
大分どーん！
Oita boom!
新曲MV公開、この後すぐ！
New song MV release, right after this!
団員さん！今年も誕生日をお祝いしてくれて本当にありがとう～
Dan-in san! Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday again this year!
新衣装＆新曲、どうだったかな？！少しでも好き～ってなってもらえたらノエちゃんとっても嬉しいです★
How were the new outfit and new song?! Noel-chan would be very happy if you like them even a little!
来年も一緒に同じ時間を過ごせますように... 大好きだよ～
I hope we can spend time together next year too... I love you!